Guide to the Leonid N. Stolovich papers M1624
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. Creative works
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti", 1980, 2003, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": correspondence (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": materials for Estonian edition (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": additional materials (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - "Subekt estetiki": correspondence (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Stolovich's reviews about abstracts of dissertations (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Stolovich's reviews about abstracts of dissertations (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - Stolovich's reviews about abstracts of dissertations (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Stolovich's reviews about various publications, including abstracts of dissertations (Box 150, Folder 8)
  - Stolovich's reviews about various publications, including abstracts of dissertations (Box 150, Folder 9)
  - Stolovich's reviews about various publications, including abstracts of dissertations (Box 150, Folder 10)
  - Stolovich's reviews about various publications, including abstracts of dissertations (Box 150, Folder 11)
  - Stolovich's reviews about various publications, including abstracts of dissertations (Box 150, Folder 12)
  - "Ob esteticheskom znachenii khudozhestvennogo obraza" (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - "Ob esteticheskom znachenii khudozhestvennogo obraza" (Box 146, Folder 11)
  - "Predmet estetiki", 1961 (Box 133, Folder 10)
  - "K voprosu o kriterii khudozhestvennosti iskusstva" (Box 146, Folder 12)
  - Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007 (Box 156, Folder 9)
  - Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007 (Box 156, Folder 10)
  - Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007 (Box 156, Folder 11)
  - Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007 (Box 156, Folder 12)
  - Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007 (Box 156, Folder 13)
  - Articles in periodicals, books and conference publications: Photocopies of title pages, tables of contents etc., 1954-2007 (Box 156, Folder 14)
  - Articles for various dictionaries and encyclopedias (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Articles for various dictionaries and encyclopedias on philosophy and aesthetics (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - Articles for various dictionaries and encyclopedias on philosophy and aesthetics (Box 145, Folder 8)
  - Articles for various dictionaries and encyclopedias on aesthetics (Box 145, Folder 9)
  - Articles for various dictionaries and encyclopedias on aesthetics (Box 145, Folder 11)
  - Articles for "Sovetskaia Entsiklopediia" (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Article on beauty for "Filosofskaia Entsiklopediia" i "Bolshaia Sovetskaia Entsiklopediia" (Box 145, Folder 10)
  - Various articles: typescripts, clippings, photocopies (Box 146, Folder 13)
  - Various articles (Box 140, Folders 6)
  - Various articles (Box 141, Folders 1)
  - Various articles (Box 141, Folders 2)
  - Various articles (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 6)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 7)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 8)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 9)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 10)
  - Various articles (Box 142, Folder 11)
  - Various articles (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Various articles (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - Various articles (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Various articles (Box 143, Folder 4)
  - Various articles (Box 146, Folder 14)
  - Various articles, 2008 (Box 156, Folder 16)
  - Various articles, 2009 (Box 156, Folder 17)
  - Various articles, 2010 (Box 156, Folder 18)
  - Various articles, 2011-2012 (Box 156, Folder 19)
  - Articles on aesthetics and art: typescripts (Box 140, Folders 1)
  - Articles on aesthetics, ethics and art: typescripts and manuscripts (Box 140, Folders 2)
  - Articles, brochures etc. (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi kategorii": Materials for the articles etc. (Box 140, Folders 3)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2005: Materials for the book (Box 140, Folders 4)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2005: Materials for the book (Box 140, Folders 5)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2005: Materials for the book, contracts with a publisher, reviews (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2005: Materials for the book (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2nd part: computer printout (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2nd part: computer printout (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2nd part: computer printout (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - "Pliuralizm v filosofii i filosofiia pliuralizma", 2005: Page-proofs (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - "Pliuralizm v filosofii i filosofiia pliuralizma", 2005: Page-proofs (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - "Pliuralizm v filosofii i filosofiia pliuralizma", 2005: Reviews (Box 141, Folder 6)
  - "Pliuralizm v filosofii i filosofiia pliuralizma", 2005: computer printout (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - "Pliuralizm v filosofii i filosofiia pliuralizma", 2005: computer printout (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - "Pliuralizm v filosofii i filosofiia pliuralizma", 2005: computer printout (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Participation in scholarly discussions on aesthetics (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Participation in scholarly discussions on aesthetics (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 5)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 6)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 7)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 8)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 9)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 10)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 11)
  - Unpublished articles (Box 143, Folder 12)
  - Unpublished works (Box 92, Folders 8)
  - Unpublished works (Box 92, Folders 9)
  - Unpublished works (Box 92, Folders 13)
  - Unpublished works (Box 92, Folders 10)
  - Unpublished works (Box 92, Folders 11)
  - Unpublished works (Box 92, Folders 12)
  - Unpublished reviews for various publishing houses (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Unpublished reviews for various publishing houses (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - "Estetika, iskusstvo, igra", 1987: Materials for the book (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - "Estetika, iskusstvo, igra", 1987: Materials for the book (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - "Estetika, iskusstvo, igra", 1987: Materials for the book (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - "Zhizn, tvorchestvo, chelovek: funktsii khudozhestvennoĭ deiatelnosti", 1985: Materials for the book (Box 139, Folder 11)
  - "Zhizn, tvorchestvo, chelovek: funktsii khudozhestvennoĭ deiatelnosti", 1985: Materials for the book (Box 139, Folder 12)
  - "Zhizn, tvorchestvo, chelovek: funktsii khudozhestvennoĭ deiatelnosti", 1985: Materials for the book (Box 139, Folder 13)
  - "Zhizn, tvorchestvo, chelovek: funktsii khudozhestvennoi deiatelnosti", 1985: Correspondence about publishing (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - "Estetika Immanuela Kanta i sovremennost": sbornik statei, 1991 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - "Istoriia russkoĭ filosofii": unpublished materials (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - "Istoriia russkoĭ filosofii": unpublished materials (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - "Istoriia russkoĭ filosofii": unpublished materials (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - "Istoriia russkoĭ filosofii": unpublished materials (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Various publications in "Akademicheskie tetradi", "Gumanitarii", "Biulleten" (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Various publications: Materialistliku dialektika pohilised seadused, Eituse eitamise sedus etc. (Box 144, Folder 9)
  - Various publicationsin "Informace a materialy", "Vytvarny zivot", "Noukogude Naine" etc. (Box 144, Folder 10)
  - Article on graphic arts by Kurt Magritz (Flat-box 40, Folder 1)
  - "Esteticheskoe v deistvitelnosti i v iskusstve", 1959: Reviews (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - "Ilu ja uhiskond", 1969: Materials for the book in Russian (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - "Ilu ja uhiskond", 1969: Materials for the book in Russian (Box 127, Folder 10)
  - "Ilu ja uhiskond", 1969: Materials for the book in Russian (Box 127, Folder 11)
  - "Kohtumised elu radadel", 2006: Reviews (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Articles in newspapers before 1994 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Articles in newspapers before 1994 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Articles in newspapers before 1994 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Articles in newspapers after 1994 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Aesthetic development program: draft (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - "Filosofiia, estetika, smekh", 1999: Materials for the book (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - "Filosofiia, estetika, smekh", 1999: Reviews (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - "Filosofiia, estetika, smekh", 1999: Materials regarding seminar on the book in University of Torino, Italy (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - "Filosofiia, estetika, smekh", 1999: Materials regarding seminar on the book in University of Torino, Italy (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - "Filosofiia, estetika, smekh", 1999: Proof-pages (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - "Filosofiia, estetika, smekh", 1999: Proof-pages (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - "Istoriia russkoi filosofii: ocherki", 2005: Reviews (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - "Stikhi i zhizn: opyt poeticheskoi avtobiografii", 2003: Reviews and correspondence (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - "Stikhi i zhizn: opyt poeticheskoi avtobiografii", 2003: Materials (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - "Stikhi i zhizn: opyt poeticheskoi avtobiografii", 2003: Page-proofs (Box 95, Folders 1)
  - "Stikhi i zhizn: opyt poeticheskoi avtobiografii", 2003: Page-proofs (Box 95, Folders 2)
  - "Vstrechi na tropakh zhizhi": Manuscript of memoir book in Russian; published in Estonian "Kohtumised elu radadel", 2005 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - On subject of aesthetics: research materials (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - On history of aesthetics (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - On history of aesthetics (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - On problems of aesthetics (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - On problems of aesthetics (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - On aesthetics and the origin of art (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - On aesthetics, art and religion (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - On aesthetics, art and religion (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - On aesthetics, art and religion (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - On aesthetics, art and religion (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - On aesthetics and realism (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - On aesthetics and social realism (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - On aesthetics and social realism (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - On aesthetics and social realism (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - On aesthetics and ethics (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - On aesthetic education (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - On aesthetic education (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - On aesthetic education (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - On aesthetic education (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - On aesthetic education (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - On aesthetic education (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - On aesthetic education and everyday life (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - On aesthetic education and everyday life (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - On aesthetic education and everyday life (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - On aesthetic education and everyday life (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - On work aesthetics (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - On work aesthetics (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - On aesthetics of everyday life (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - On aesthetics of everyday life (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - On aesthetics of everyday life (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - On aesthetics of everyday life (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - On aesthetic needs (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - On aesthetic needs (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - On aesthetic taste (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - On aesthetic value (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - On aesthetics and sociology (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - On aesthetics and sociology (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - On aesthetic sociology (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - On sociology (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - On sociology (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - On sociology (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - On aesthetic experiences (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - On aesthetic attitude to reality (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - On aesthetics and nature (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - On public entity of aesthetics (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - On aesthetics in foreign countries (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - On art and play (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - On art and play (Box 139, Folder 10)
  - On art and play (Box 139, Folder 11)
  - On functions of art (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - On subject of art (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - On sociology of art (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - On sociology of art (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - On specific character of art (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - On content and form of art (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - On content and form of art (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - On specific character of art (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - On specific character of art (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - On art work and method (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - On art work and method (Box 131, Folder 11)
  - On art work and method (Box 131, Folder 12)
  - On personality and art (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - On personality and art (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - On art and alienation (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - On art and alienation (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - On art and alienation (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - On art and science (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - On beauty (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - On beauty (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - On ideal (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - On Ideal (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - On tragedy (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - On problem of the comic (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - On art and national unity (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - On art and national unity (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - On worldview and creativity (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - On art and society (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - On art and communism (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - On art and communism (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - On art and fascism (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - The arts (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - The arts (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - "Esteticheskaia i khudozhestvennaia tsennost: sushchnost, spetsifika, sootnoshenie": typescript, 1982 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - "Esteticheskaia i khudozhestvennaia tsennost: sushchnost, spetsifika, sootnoshenie": reviews, agreement with the publisher etc. (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - "Esteticheskaia i khudozhestvennaia tsennost: sushchnost, spetsifika, sootnoshenie": typescript and letters (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti", 1972: Materials for the book (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti", 1972: Materials for the book (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti", 1972: Materials for the book (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti", 1972: Materials for the book (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": Typescript different from 1972 edition (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": Typescript different from 1972 edition (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": Typescript different from 1972 edition (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - "Priroda esteticheskoi tsennosti": In Estonian (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - "Esteticheskoe i khudozhestvennoe v dizaine", 1977: unpublished (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - "Esteticheskaia tsennost i problema otsenki", 1982: unpublished (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - "Esteticheskaia tsennost i problema otsenki", 1982: unpublished (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - "Esteticheskaia tsennost i problema otsenki", 1982: unpublished (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - "Razrobotka teoreticheskikh osnov formirovaniia esteticheskoi tsennosti promyshlennykh izdelii", unpublished (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Publications in various newspapers (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Preparatory materials for various articles (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Preparatory materials for various articles (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Preparatory materials for various articles (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Preparatory materials for various articles (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Recent publications, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Typescript (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Typescript (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Typescript (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Typescript (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Typescript (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Print (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Print (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Print (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Print (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 123, Folder 10)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Materials for the book (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii", 1994: Print (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii". Agreement with the publisher, 1994 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - "Krasota, dobro, istina: ocherk istorii esteticheskoi aksiologii": reviews, letters (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Responses to L.N. Stolovich's publications in various newspapers (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Responses to L.N. Stolovich's publications in various newspapers (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Responses to L.N. Stolovich's publications in various newspapers (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Responses to L.N. Stolovich's publications in various newspapers (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Responses to L.N. Stolovich's publications in various newspapers (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Responses to L.N. Stolovich's publications in various newspapers (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Copies and reprints of articles: various periodicals, various languages (Box 94, Folders 1)
  - Copies and reprints of articles: various periodicals, various languages (Box 94, Folders 2)
  - Copies and reprints of articles: various periodicals, various languages (Box 94, Folders 3)
  - Copies and reprints of articles: various periodicals, various languages (Box 94, Folders 4)
  - Copies and reprints of articles: various periodicals, various languages (Box 94, Folders 5)
  - Copies and reprints of articles: various periodicals, various languages (Box 94, Folders 6)
  - "On taste": Responses to the article, 1963-1965 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of L.N. Stolovich's publications (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Reviews of L.N. Stolovich's publications (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of L.N. Stolovich's publications (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Reviews of L.N. Stolovich's publications (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of L.N. Stolovich's publications (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - Reviews of L.N. Stolovich's publications (Box 128, Folder 13)
  - Bibliography of published works (Box 146, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography of published works, lectures, conference attendance (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography of published works, lectures, conference attendance (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Review of the book: Gulyga, A.V. Principles of aesthetics, 1987 (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Subject of philosophy: various materials (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Theory of knowledge (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Matter (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Consciousness (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Dialectics as science (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Law of the unity (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Categories of dialectics (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Miscellaneous handwritten notes (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Various articles (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Various materials (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Bibliography (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Bibliography (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Lectures on dialectical materialism: Bibliography (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - "Esteticheskoe v deistvitelnosti i v iskusstve", 1959: First version (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - "Esteticheskoe v deistvitelnosti i v iskusstve", 1959: First version (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - "Esteticheskoe v deistvitelnosti i v iskusstve", 1959: First version (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - "Esteticheskoe v deistvitelnosti i v iskusstve", 1959: First version (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - "Kategoriia prekrasnogo i obshchestvennyi ideal": Materials for the 2nd edition (unrealized) (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - "Prekrasnoe v zhizni i v iskusstve", 1964: First version (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - "Osnovy marksistko-leninskoi estetiki": Materials for the textbook (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - "Esteticheskie vzgliady Aristotelia, 1948: Student's paper (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - "V.I. Lenin i I.V. Stalin o narodnosti iskusstva", 1952: B.A./M.A. Thesis (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - On Albert Einstein and Tartu University (Box 128, Folder 11)
  - On Kant (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - On Kant (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - On Kant and his archives (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - Handwritten notes on philosophy, literature, art etc. (Box 126, Folder 1)